The problem with scaling gradient descent is simple.
勾配降下法のスケーリングに関する問題は簡単です
You need to compute these gradients.
これらの勾配を計算する必要があります
Here's another rule of thumb.
これは別の経験則です
If computing your loss takes n floating point operations,
損失の計算にn個の浮動小数点演算がある場合
computing its gradient takes about three times that compute.
その勾配の計算にはその約3倍の計算が必要です
As we saw earlier,
前に見たように
this last function is huge.
この損失関数は巨大です
It depends on every single element in your training set.
トレーニングセットに含まれるすべての単一要素に依存します
That can be a lot of compute if your data set is big,
データセットが大きければ大量の計算が必要であり
and we want to be able to train on lots of data because in practice,
大量のデータをトレーニングできる必要があります
on real problems, you'll always get more gains,
なぜなら 現実の問題では常に
the more data you use.
使うデータが多いほど成果も多くなるからです
And because gradient descent is iterative,
勾配降下法は反復的であるため
you have to do that for many steps.
多くのステップに対して行う必要があります
That means going through your data tens or hundreds of times. That's not good.
つまり データを何十回または何百回も処理することになります  これはよくありません
So instead, we're going to cheat.
代わりに ずるをします
Instead of computing the loss,
損失を計算する代わりに
we're going to compute an estimate of it,
その推定を計算します
a very bad estimate,
非常に悪い推定です
a terrible estimate, in fact.
実際 ひどい推定です
That estimate is going to be so bad,
とてもひどい推定なので
you might wonder why it works at all.
なぜうまくいくのか不思議に思うでしょう
And you would be right because we're going to
それは正しい感想です  なぜなら さらにましなものに
also have to spend some time making it less terrible.
するために 少し時間をかける必要があります
The estimate we're going to use is simply computing
使おうとしている推定では トレーニングデータの
the average loss for a very small random fraction of the training data.
非常に小さいランダムな一部分に対する平均損失を単純に計算します
Think between one and a thousand training samples each time.
毎回 1～1000のトレーニングサンプルを考えます
I say random because it's very important.
ランダムという言葉を使ったのは それが非常に重要なためです
If the way you pick your samples isn't random enough,
サンプルの選択方法が十分にランダムではない場合
it no longer works at all.
この方法はうまくいかなくなります
So we're going to take a very small sliver of the training data,
それでは これから トレーニングデータのごく一部分を取得し
compute the loss for that sample,
そのサンプルの損失を計算し
compute the derivative for that sample,
そのサンプルの微分を計算して
and pretend that that derivative is the right direction to use to do gradient descent.
その微分が勾配降下法に使用するのに正しい方向であるふりをします
It is not at all the right direction.
まったく正しい方向ではありません
And, in fact, at times,
実際
it might increase the real loss, not reduce it.
実際の損失を減らすのではなく増やす場合さえあります
But we're going to compensate by doing this many,
しかし これを何回も何回も行い
many times, taking very,
そのたびにきわめて小さいステップを使うことで
very small steps each time.
補正します
So each step is a lot cheaper to compute,
そのため 各ステップの計算負荷ははるかに小さくなりますが
but we pay a price.
その代償が必要です
We have to take many more smaller steps instead of one large step.
1つの大きいステップではなく 多数の小さいステップを使用する必要があります
On balance though, we win by a lot.
とはいっても 結局は大きなメリットがあります
In fact, as you'll see in the assignments,
実際 課題を見るとわかるように
doing this is vastly more efficient than doing gradient decent.
勾配降下法を行うより この方がはるかに効率的です
This technique is called stochastic gradient descent,
この技法は確率的勾配降下法と呼ばれ
and is at the core of deep learning.
ディープラーニングの核心部分です
That's because stochastic gradient descent scales well with both data and model size,
これは 確率的勾配降下法がデータとモデルサイズの両方のスケーリングによく対応できるためであり
and we want both big data and big models.
ここではビッグデータとビッグモデルの両方が必要です
Stochastic gradient descent, SGD for short,
確率的勾配降下法(SGD)は
is nice and scalable.
優れたスケーラブルな技法です
But because it's fundamentally a pretty bad optimizer
しかし 基本的にはかなり悪いオプティマイザーであり
that happens to be the only one that's fast enough,
十分に速い方法がたまたまこれしかないから使うのであって
it comes with a lot of issues in.
実際には多くの問題が発生します